<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Space Futures Initiative</title>
    <link>http://spacefuturesinitiative.org/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Space Futures Initiative</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://spacefuturesinitiative.org/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adapting Land Value Taxation to Space</title>
      <link>http://spacefuturesinitiative.org/posts/land-value-taxation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacefuturesinitiative.org/posts/land-value-taxation/</guid>
      <description>Adapting Land Value Taxation to Space Taxation and Space Taxation is Essential to Governance Taxation finances the modern state and makes it possible for governments to supply public goods, insure risks, shape behavior, and make economic activity more legible to the public.
In order to establish effective government in space, tax policy must be adapted to the celestial realm.
The proliferation of modern space activities and the potential for future transformations in spacefaring through new technologies suggest that it is worth considering how space activities beyond Earth’s orbit will be governed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New Game in the Space Industry</title>
      <link>http://spacefuturesinitiative.org/posts/the-new-game-in-the-space-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacefuturesinitiative.org/posts/the-new-game-in-the-space-industry/</guid>
      <description>The space industry as we know it today has been the result of a revolution that began at the beginning of the last decade. Until very recently, space was considered a domain for the few, where only governments of the most powerful nations on Earth could set its course. This article takes a quick and brief look at the transformations of the sector in recent years and explores the amazing opportunities that both now and in the future, the space sector can reach to change humanity for good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Policy Memo: Active Orbital Debris Removal</title>
      <link>http://spacefuturesinitiative.org/posts/active-orbital-debris-removal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacefuturesinitiative.org/posts/active-orbital-debris-removal/</guid>
      <description>The United States should encourage the commercial development of active orbital debris removal technology.
It is our duty as a global space industry leader to take the first steps to mitigate the dangerous buildup of orbital debris, which usually originates from defunct satellites and can both damage existing satellites and prevent launches. China is the only state to have publicly demonstrated the physical disposal of a dead satellite by another satellite, also known as active debris removal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space Governance with Carson Ezell - The Good Pod</title>
      <link>http://spacefuturesinitiative.org/posts/carson-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacefuturesinitiative.org/posts/carson-podcast/</guid>
      <description>SFI Director Carson Ezell was interviewed by Nathan Barnard on The Good Pod, a podcast showcasing conversations &amp;ldquo;thinking about the best way to help people&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Threat of Hypersonic Weapons in the New Arms Race</title>
      <link>http://spacefuturesinitiative.org/posts/threat-hypersonic-carson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://spacefuturesinitiative.org/posts/threat-hypersonic-carson/</guid>
      <description>In late 2021, a missile launched above the atmosphere released a device that raced toward its target at hypersonic speed, concluding a successful test of a hypersonic glide vehicle for China. The test temporarily brought the race to develop hypersonic capabilities into the headlines, but it has been well underway for years.  
Hypersonic weapons are among the most recent advanced technologies being developed by top militaries globally to maintain strategic advantage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
